# 你看看熟了这个
See, this is fully cooked
# 一敲咔咔
Tap on it, "Ka-ka" (mimic the sound)
# 里头的肉丸是硬的齐了
When the meat filling is hard, it’s done.
# 咬一小口
Take a small bite
# 唰那汤流出来的时候
The juice spread out instantly
# 啊呀那种感觉太棒了
What a wonderful feeling that is!
# 宋军 干爹干爹
Jun Song! Honorary father!
# 大爷好
Hello, Da Ye
# 宋军好
Hello, Song Jun
# 和面 今儿做什么啊
Mixing dough. What are we making today?
# 今儿做门丁
Today we are making Doornail meat pie
# 门丁肉饼
Doornail meat pie
# 咱先和面啊 高筋粉
Let’s mix dough first. Use high gluten flour
# 这可是你们家的看家的玩意儿
This is the trump card of your restaurant!
# 谢谢大爷
Thanks for the compliment, Da Ye
# 用是凉水温水
Use cold or warm water?
# 温水喝多少水
Warm water
# 搁多少水呢
How much?
# 一斤面六两水
Six “liang” (300 grams) of water per “jin” (500 grams) of flour
# 一斤面怎么也得六两水
At least six “liang” (300 grams) of water per “jin” (500 grams) of flour
# 就相当于烙饼面呗
It’s similar to making dough for Chinese pancakes
# 对是吧
Yes indeed
# 是吧
Yes
# 老门框的涮羊肉
Lamb hotpot,
# 还有这门丁肉饼
and the Doornail meat pie
# 好多网友特别喜欢吃
are two of the most popular dishes in Lao-Men-Kuang.
# 这个是老北京的记忆
This pie contains the old memories of Beijing
# 但是我觉得做得最好
But I think the most delicious (Doornail meat pie)
# 还是宋军他们家
is made by Song Jun’s restaurant
# 你看一咬一口汤汁唰又出来了
Take a bite and then the juice is spreading out
# 你看这面和的
Look at how we knead the dough,
# 必须得润 必须得和到位
Must knead utill the dough is smooth
# 不到位不行
You cannot be lazy when kneading the dough
# 一点疙瘩都不行
The dough should not have any clumps.
# 这手有劲你看 有劲
See, he has a lot of strength.
# 你看这小胖手多有劲
This pair of cutie chubby hands have the strength!
# 没问题
No problem!
# 这面差不多了
The dough is almost ready
# 必须的
Of course
# 必须得润
It must be smooth and even
# 好嘞
Great!
# 和到润了 必须润了
Knead the dough until it is even and smooth
# 然后醒一下
Then let it rest for a while
# 你看这里边什么都没加
We didn’t add anything else other than flour and water
# （把面）这封上
Cover the dough with cling film while resting
# 你看这小面醒这
Let the dough rest
# 由于烙馅（饼）和这面更（得）醒开了
It is critical to rest the dough long enough, especially for making meat pie
# 是吧
Sure
# 好
Good
# 洗洗手 洗洗手
Wash hands
# 洗洗手弄那个花椒水
Next, we make Sichuan pepper extract
# 下一步该泡花椒了
Soak the Sichuan pepper with water
# 花椒水
Sichuan pepper extract
# 拿热水 开水
Use boiling hot water
# 拿一把花椒
take a handful of Sichuan pepper
# 花椒
Sichuan pepper
# 来点花椒啊
Bring me some Sichuan pepper
# 今天用的是牛肉
Today we use beef
# 是吧
There it is
# 这牛肉很好
This piece of beef looks great
# 你看这牛肉真新鲜
It is very fresh
# 花椒
Sichuan pepper
# 这花椒得用什么
What do we do with the pepper?
# 用开水泡泡
Soaking it with boiling hot water? - Yes
# 一百六十克水
Add about 160 grams of water
# 花椒有多少
How much pepper?
# 花椒有半两二十五克
about 25 grams of Sichuan pepper
# 这个用开水充分的激发出花椒的香味
Use boiling hot water to fully extract the aroma of the Sichuan pepper
# 这会该剁馅
Now let's chop and mince the beef
# 两斤肉啊
Two “jin” (1 kg) of beef
# 牛肉这是胸口
We use beef brisket
# 因为它有带油
Because it contains enough fat
# 有油才香
The fat brings a nice aroma to the filling,
# 肉才不柴
And makes it tender
# 不能凑合
We can’t compromise the quality
# 肉要好要干松
The beef should feel dry and loose
# 你看这肉是吧
Look at this piece of beef
# 吃到嘴里一点水汽没有
When you eat the meat filling made from it, no excess moisture will remain
# 它原材料是第一
This depends first on the quality of the meat
# 第二就是和发
Second on how you mix the filling
# 二伯啊 哎
Er Bai. - Yes?
# 你得好好介绍一下宋军
You should introduce Song Jun
# 宋军就是老门框的掌柜的
Song Jun is the owner
# 也是当家人
And the head chef of Lao-Men-Kuang restaurant
# 既是干儿子
He is my pseudo son
# 是吧
Yeah
# 也是徒弟
And my disciple
# 你看啊大爷
Look, Da Ye,
# 所有的门丁肉饼不能用绞肉机绞
The meat used for Doornail meat pie should not be ground by machine
# （要）用手切馅
It needs to be chopped
# 然后剁
and minced by hand
# 为什么要剁
The reason to chop and mince by hand instead of by machine is that
# 它绞完以后不腻乎容易泄
Ground meat (by machine) is not sticky enough
# 它不往一块走
The meat does not stick together
# 腻乎就是抱团儿
Sticky means they can form meatballs easily
# 而且剁中粗就可以了
Also, we only need to mince it to medium rough
# 中粗它有嚼劲儿
Medium rough makes the final meat filling al dente, tenderly chewy
# 还越嚼越香
And taste better as we chew
# 一咬开一点皮吧
Take a small bite of the crust
# 咬一小口
Take a small bit
# 唰那汤流出来的时候
The meat juice spread out immediately
# 你能感觉太棒了
It feels so good
# 就是好吃的
Just delicious
# 我期待着
I look forward to it
# 毫无保留
Without hiding any secrets
# 我们该怎么做就怎么做
We will cook it as it should be cooked (in the restaurant)
# 但是头一次用
But this is my first time cooking it with
# 家用电饼铛
an electric griddle baking pan for home use
# 争取还原到店里的
I will try my best to reproduce the one we make in restaurant
# 这种效果
The same quality and taste
# 电饼铛咱们这个温度上
The temperature settings of the electric griddle baking pans
# 也有点区别
Are different
# 大爷这个铛我都没使过
I have never used Da Ye's electric pan.
# 你没使过这是新买的
Of course you haven’t! This is new.
# 就为宋军这次来
Since Song Jun is coming,
# 特地买了一个
I bought this specifically for him.
# 我要做不好的
If I don’t cook the best Doornail meat pie,
# 都对不起这铛
I will fail this new baking pan!
# 对
Yes!
# 差不多了
Almost done
# 成了你这不沾刀 不沾刀
It’s done! The meat does not stick to the knife
# 你看倍儿细腻
See how even and fine the minced beef is
# 好
Great!
# 搁一旁
Put it aside
# 好
Good
# 我给你说我真欣赏宋军
To be honest, I truly admire Song Jun
# 切点姜
Chop some ginger
# 下一步搁料油先炸洋葱
Next, we add some herbal oil: first deep fry onion
# 抽吧了以后捞出来
We fry until the onion shrinks completely then take out the onion, keep the oil;
# 再继续搁大葱香葱香菜根
Then we add spring onions, scallion, cilantro root
# 都是干了以后
Fry until they are dehydrated
# 一层层炸
one by one
# 炸到最后
Eventually,
# 我干爹出了一招
My honorary father (Er Bai) had an idea
# 搁个大菠萝
Put a big pineapple in, and fry it.
# 再把菠萝炸抽了以后捞出来
Fry until the pineapple is dehydrated and then take it out
# 满屋子都是香味是真香
The whole room is filled with aroma, it is really fragrant.
# 倒里了
Herbal oil in
# 料油
Herbal oil
# 这边有小二两油
About two “liang” (100 grams) of oil
# 为什么好吃的
The key to the delicious meat pie
# 就在这
Is right here
# 牛肉馅必须得油多点大一点（才）香
Beef meat filling needs more oil to taste good
# 然后黄酱 六必居的鲜黄酱
Then we add fresh yellow soybean paste from Liu Bi Ju
# 老北京的鲜黄酱
This is traditional Peking style fresh yellow soybean paste
# 再来点鸡蛋清
Then we add egg white
# 搁鸡蛋清
Egg white from two eggs
# 它还能拢一块
It helps the meat filling to stick together
# 下一步
Next step
# 花椒水
Sichuan pepper extract, in
# 北京的花椒
This is Peking style Sichuan pepper
# 用黄豆酱油
Add soybean soy sauce
# 五十克
Fifty grams
# 你看到没有
See
# 五十好
Now fifty grams
# 味极鲜
Seasoning soy sauce
# 五十克
Fifty grams
# 老抽四十（克）
Dark soy sauce, forty grams
# 这三样搁齐了
That’s the three ingredients
# 这脑袋是好使了
Such a smart brain!
# 都记下来
He memorizes everything
# 然后咱们再来一点点香油
Then we add a little sesame oil
# 来一勺就够了
One teaspoon is enough
# OK
OK
# 不搁盐
We don’t need to add salt
# 不搁味粉
No need for MSG
# 不搁鸡粉
No need for chicken flavored powder
# 为什么充分的体验
Why? Because in this way we taste
# 就是原汁原味淡一些
the original flavor. Not too salty
# 不要吃的太咸
Don’t eat too much salt
# 他为什么不慢慢加在这
Do you know why he didn’t add the ingredient step by step but all at once?
# 它的肉好肉要不行的话
Because the quality of meat is very good, otherwise
# 它一点点吃水
the meat can only mix with water bit by bit
# 最主要的还有一点
Another important trick here
# 咱们就这蔬菜汁去腥
We use vegetable juice to get rid of the bad odor and flavor of the meat
# 这厉害这个
This is impressive
# 切点胡萝卜
We slice some carrots
# 香菜
Cilantro
# 对
Right
# 洋葱
Onions
# OK
OK
# 蔬菜汁就是上次的时候
Last time, my master (means Er Bai here)
# 我师傅特意教我的
Taught me how to make and use the vegetable juice
# 那味儿 这里边就缺个芹菜
This smell good. Only missing Chinese celery here.
# 你看这个手劲
See how hard he squeezes the vegetables to get the juice
# 蔬菜的香味
The aroma of the vegetables
# 全都融入到这个
are completely extracted out
# 汁儿里
into the juice
# 如果说我们家里边有那个啥
If we have blender or juicer at home
# 榨汁机榨点汁更好
It’s even better to use it to get the vegetable juice
# OK了
OK
# 来了
Now it’s done
# 好
Great!
# 我先还得一有一个最重要的
One of the most important tricks
# 我不搁大葱
I don’t use spring onions here
# 我搁紫葱头不能搁白的
I will use purple onion
# 白的臭
Do not use white onion as it smells bad
# 紫的是甜的
Purple onion is sweet
# 对
Right
# 这个必须最后搁
The chopped purple onion has to be mixed in last
# 就是和完馅以后
Which means after everything else is mixed into the meat
# 什么时候包
When we start to put fillings into the shell
# 什么时候搁
We put the chopped onions in.
# 这个也不能剁
The purple onion should not be minced
# 必须得切
You have to cut it
# 就是把眼睛辣死也得切
even if the onion makes you cry
# 它一剁味就变了
If you mince it, it tastes different
# 好勒
OK
# 切这一个吧
We need one onion
# 对
Right
# 是吧
Yes
# 这葱头切的可不少
There are plenty of onions
# 来和馅
Let’s mix the fillings
# 算一算
Calculate to scale up or down
# 把这些汁均匀的渗透到肉里
Blend all the liquid into the meat
# 如果家里的网友就掌握不好量
If you are not sure how much liquid to add
# 可以自己慢慢往里注入
You can add in the liquid slowly
# 不要像我是一下加完开始打
Do not add everything in all at once then blend like I did
# 顺时针
(blend) clockwise
# 不要像小宋似的啊
You don’t need to do it as Xiao Song does
# 一下加足了因为他劲儿大
It is only because he has the strength to mix everything together
# 这就是一次性加完了
This is what is like if you add everything together
# 确实对自己来说费点劲
It is a bit difficult for me
# 那是
Of course
# 你看打馅
See how he mixes the meat filling
# 不停的搅
Stir with his hand constantly
# 跟那转速似的
His speed looks like a mixing machine!
# 这样
In this way,
# 它不懈
The filling can stick together
# 有点喘了
He is in short breath now
# 大爷您知道为什么他有点费劲吗
Do you know why he has difficulty mixing, Da Ye?
# 他那盆小转不开
His mixing bowl is too small
# 要不然我替你打两下
May I help you with the mixing?
# 别别别别别
No thanks!
# 我给你换一盆
Switch to a larger bowl
# 来放里头
Put it in
# 这刚才是这么顺时针打的
We mixed clockwise before
# 咱们这么一推
Pour the fillings in
# 还是那么顺
We should continue to stir clockwise
# 不能乱
Do not change the direction
# 这行 这行了吧
Now it’s done
# 店里全是标准化
In the restaurant, we standardize every step
# 但是在这儿咱们就得试
But here (at home) we need to try it out
# 这馅好了
The filling is done
# 打着粘稠有劲儿粘手
Stir until it becomes very viscous and sticky to the hand
# 而且你看拢到一块了
They stick together
# 黏在一起了
# 是吧
Right
# 这洋葱加不加
Should we add the chopped onions now?
# 洋葱待会 什么时候包什么时候加
No, we wait until we are ready to fold the filling into the shell
# 开始铛馅饼
We start to preheat the baking pan and select meat pie baking mode
# 咱们定到八分钟
Let’s set for 8 minutes baking
# 八分钟开始
Hit start
# 上下铛一会就全热了
The baking pan will be ready very soon
# 这面也醒的差不多了
Now the dough has rested long enough.
# 这手法还挺熟的
You are very skilled!
# 这东西就是
There you go
# 揉完面揉润揉润以后
Knead the dough again until smooth
# 给它做成剂子条
Rub the dough into long strips
# 咱们揪剂子不切
We pull the dough strip into small pieces, not cutting it
# 揪的小一点
We need small pieces
# 十六克是吧
About 16 grams each piece, right?
# 今天您呈现的就是门丁
Today you demonstrate Doornail meat pie
# 你在大了
If the shell is bigger
# 就叫馅饼
It becomes normal meat pie
# 在大的就叫肉饼
If you make even larger shell, then it is called meatloaf pie.
# 下一步就来馅倒洋葱
Now we can add the chopped onion into the filling
# 对
Good
# 这会儿现包现倒洋葱啊
Only add the onion when we start making the pie.
# 现包现拌
Mix onions as we make the pie
# 因为为什么要洋葱
Why we add onions?
# 洋葱是跟它合在一起
We want to blend the onion in
# 让它融入到馅里
To mix it well into the filling
# 烤是为了让它融入到馅里
Baking will further mix it into the filling
# 葱头和牛肉是绝配
Onions pair well with beef
# 大爷您说的对
You are right, Da Ye
# 好
Nice
# 擀皮儿
Now we make the shell
# 这剂子可不小了
This shell is pretty big already
# 咱先包一个
Let’s try to make one first
# 包的手法
The technique we use to make the Doornail meat pie
# 就是老北京的那种包子的感觉
is similar to making traditional Peking style Bao Zi (steamed bun dumpling)
# 包包子的感觉
Feels like making Bao Zi
# 一捏褶 OK
Fold the shell like this, OK
# 翻过来搁
Put it aside upside down
# 好了
Finished
# 上盘你看看
Check on the baking pan now
# 淋点油
A little oil, in
# 拿刷子一刷
Brush it evenly
# 不要多
Not too much oil
# 烤盘一定要选深的
A deep baking pan is necessary
# 咱们是3.5
We use 3.5-centimeter-deep pan
# 其他都是2.5
Others usually use 2.5-centimeter-deep pan
# 进锅的时候
When we put the meat pie into the baking pan
# 口朝上
we put them the folding-side up
# 口朝上为什么呢
Why?
# 它底下不平
Because its bottom side is not flat yet
# 先把低下烙平
We fry it flat first
# 齐了
Done
# 稍微搁一会儿
We close the lid and bake for a while
# 不能把上面这层
You don’t want to bake the upper layer
# 烤老了 一烤干了
for too long. Otherwise, it is too dry.
# 翻过来就漏了
it will crack and leak once you turn it over
# 可以了
This is nice
# 上气了
Steam is coming out
# 好来了
Good
# 底下考焦干了
The bottom is now brown and crispy
# 翻盖   等一下盖盖儿
Turn the meat pie over, and bake the other side with the lid closed
# 最基本的检查方法
The basic way to check whether it is ready,
# 就是你一敲咔咔里头的肉丸是硬的
Is to tap the pie with your finger and feels the hardness of the meat filling. If the filling is hard,
# 齐了
It’s done and ready to serve.
# 你看看熟了那就
See they are well-cooked now
# 好了
Great
# 没问题
No problem
# 家里饼铛就这样
That’s the best a home electric baking pan can do
# 听声就齐了
Listen to the sound, it’s done.
# 大爷您来一下 来一个
Have one, Da Ye!
# 你给大爷拿一个
Help Da Ye to choose one.
# 随便您看
Whichever one you like
# 哪个都行 啊呀
Anyone is fine.
# 你看看 你看看
Look at this
# 特香 嘎嘎的脆
Super delicious, "Ga-ga" crispy
# 皮是脆的
The crust is crispy
# 慢点别呲了
Be careful, don't leak the soup inside
# 那汤别呲了
Mind the hot soup!
# 这个条件再好点
If we have better cooking conditions
# 如果拿到店里面做
If we make it in our restaurant
# 比这肯定还好 好多了肯定
It will taste even better, much better
# 店里它的火力足
In the restaurant the heating power is much higher
# 这包的严实
The pie is folded well
# 快点吃
Eat quickly
# 我给你照
I will record for you
# 皮酥 酥完
The outside is crispy
# 酥中里边带这那个肉
Inside the crust, there is the meat filling
# 这肉呢 尤其这肉肉太香了
The meat filling is so flavorful and delicious
# 而且不柴嗯
And it is not too chewy
# 调味调的太准了
The filling was seasoned precisely
# 也不愧为是
No wonder
# 老门框的招牌
this is the chef special of Lao-Men-Kuang restaurant
# 谢谢
Thank you!
# 这个记得要点在哪
Let’s recall the key point of the recipe:
# 肉馅皮你看到没有
Meat filling recipe; shell making, see;
# 和的面
how we made the dough
# 非常关键
These are all very important
# 大爷是不是
Am I right, Da Ye?
# 都做了标准
He sets the standard
# 你看那
See,
# 它吃起来不梗
It is not too chewy
# 又酥是面的
It is crispy on the outside,
# 它又软
Also soft and tender
# 我觉得宋军这馅儿和得好
I think Song Jun made great filling
# 你说您说的是面
You complimented on the crust
# 我说的是馅儿
I praised about the filling
# 您说的是面儿
You talked about the outside
# 我说的是里儿
I talked about the inside
# 二斤肉
Two “jin” (1 kg) meat
# 二十克的酱
Twenty grams of yellow soybean paste
# 五十克的酱油和生抽
Fifty grams of soy sauce and light soy sauce
# 然后还有四十克的老抽
Forty grams of dark soy sauce
# 这要家里过去的
If we used traditional
# 煤气的那个饼铛
baking pan over gas heating at home
# 更好比这个好
It would be better
# 越现代的越干
The modern one makes the meat pie dryer
# 宋军经常来我们老饭骨
Please come to “Master Chef” more often, Song Jun!
# 谢谢大爷
Thank you, Da Ye!
# 我们老饭骨时刻欢迎你
We "Lao Fan Gu" always welcome you!
# 谢谢 谢谢
Thank you very much!
# 带来更多的好吃的 美食
Bring us more delicious food
# 给大家带来更多惊喜
Bring us more surprise!
# 好 好
Sure thing!